<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        BASIC blog full text feed    </title>
        <link href="/research/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2019-04-23T20:16:11Z</updated>

    <id>/research/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">Simulation of Multiphase Flow Systems for Ophtalmic Applications</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/universal-2018.html"/>
            <updated>2019-01-08T11:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2019-01-08T11:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/universal-2018.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/cnpq.png&#34; /&gt;
The numerical simulation is an important tool to solve two-phase flow
problems found in several engineering processes, such as oil drilling,
reservoir filling and cooling of electronic components. In medicine,
it has been shown an efficient tool for the study of biological
problems, such as corneal replacement, the latter of great importance
for patients in need of transplant.
It is in this scope that this project retains, for the development and
improvement of a two-phase study platform using high level numerical
simulations, in order to characterize the dynamics of bubbles in outer
layers of the cular body whe the replacement of the cornea is required.
Through the Big Bubble technique, where bubbles are inserted into the
outer layers of the eyeball to corneal&amp;nbsp;detachment.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">4th Workshop on Advances in CFD and modeling of Interface Dynamics in Capillary Two-Phase Flows</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/paep-2018.html"/>
            <updated>2019-01-08T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2019-01-08T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/paep-2018.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/capes.png&#34; /&gt;
This document presents the proposal of the Organizing Committee of the
4th Workshop on Advances in &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CFD&lt;/span&gt; and Modeling of Interface Dynamics in
Capillary Two-Phase Flows, to be held in the city of Rio de Janeiro - &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;RJ&lt;/span&gt;
in May 2019. It is a worldwide event, held in continuously since 2015
(Lausanne - Switzerland), and the next one in Kobe - Japan in October
2018, where the current workshop will be held in Brazil for the first
time in 2019.
This workshop’s subject is related to the important area
of multiphase flow with applications to engineering and other related
areas. The estimated number of participants is limited to 60 graduated
students. The team of this workshop is composed of by researchers and
professors from international universities of high recognition in acade-
mics and research, from Japan, England and Switzerland, as well as from
Rio de Janeiro. The areas of knowledge related to the event are:
Variational Principles and Numerical Methods (3.05.01.04-0), Fluid
Mechanics (3.05.01.02-4), Heat Transfer (3.05.01.01-6), Gas Dynamics
(3.05.01.03-2) and Thermodynamics&amp;nbsp;(3.05.02.01-2).&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">4th Workshop on Advances in CFD and modeling of Interface Dynamics in Capillary Two-Phase Flows</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/arc-2018.html"/>
            <updated>2019-01-07T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2019-01-07T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/arc-2018.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/cnpq.png&#34; /&gt;
This document presents the proposal of the Organizing Committee of the
4th Workshop on Advances in &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CFD&lt;/span&gt; and Modeling of Interface Dynamics in
Capillary Two-Phase Flows, to be held in the city of Rio de Janeiro - &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;RJ&lt;/span&gt;
in May 2019. It is a worldwide event, held in continuously since 2015
(Lausanne - Switzerland), and the next one in Kobe - Japan in October
2018, where the current workshop will be held in Brazil for the first
time in 2019.
This workshop’s subject is related to the important area
of multiphase flow with applications to engineering and other related
areas. The estimated number of participants is limited to 60 graduated
students. The team of this workshop is composed of by researchers and
professors from international universities of high recognition in acade-
mics and research, from Japan, England and Switzerland, as well as from
Rio de Janeiro. The areas of knowledge related to the event are:
Variational Principles and Numerical Methods (3.05.01.04-0), Fluid
Mechanics (3.05.01.02-4), Heat Transfer (3.05.01.01-6), Gas Dynamics
(3.05.01.03-2) and Thermodynamics&amp;nbsp;(3.05.02.01-2).&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Smart Thermal Management of High-Power Microprocessors Using Phase-Change</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/thermasmart-2017.html"/>
            <updated>2017-10-30T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2017-10-30T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/thermasmart-2017.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="cooling of electronics"
                        label="Cooling Of Electronics" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/eu.png&#34; /&gt;
Developments in modern high-speed microprocessors enhance communication,
computing and electronics, thereby playing a profound role in our
societies and industries. Sustaining long-term high speeds and reliable
operation requires efficient heat dissipation. Phase-change based
cooling offers a promising alternative to conventional air-cooling in
both earth and space environments.
We will build on our previous &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FP7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IRSES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;THERMAPOWER&lt;/span&gt; project which led to
major advancements in the fundamental understanding of phase change
phenomena. As a result of this early work one researcher won an
international prize and secured a fellowship at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; following the
discovery of azimuthal currents in evaporating drops. We aim to achieve
this through the expansion of our network, building new collaborations
of top researchers from 15 world-class universities from &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt;, Asia,
Africa, North America and South America, and 3 European SMEs with
expertise in precision experiments, micro- fabrication, theoretical
modelling, numerical simulation and engineering design. This
collaboration will enable knowledge transfer and access to unique
facilities at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;, Intel, Brazilian Furnas, Hitachi, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;, Indian &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TIFR&lt;/span&gt;,
Toronto &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SIE&lt;/span&gt; Lab, Tianjin Key Lab and Pretoria Thermofluid Lab, training
43 early stage researchers in latest experimental and modelling
techniques. The research programme planned addresses key questions in
complexities of scale hitherto unstudied, including contact line
interactions amongst evaporating bubbles or droplet populations on
patterned substrates. The expertise will be transferred through the
planned secondments and exposure of all secondees to different research
environments. Besides regular meetings and technical workshops, we will
hold training schools at Maryland, Kyushu, Toronto, Warsaw and
Edinburgh. This will consolidate the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt;’s position at the forefront of
cutting-edge research in this area and will promote a long lasting
collaboration between Academia and&amp;nbsp;Industry.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Multiphase System for Cooling of Electronics</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/emergentes-2016.html"/>
            <updated>2016-12-02T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2016-12-02T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/emergentes-2016.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="cooling of electronics"
                        label="Cooling Of Electronics" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/faperj.png&#34; /&gt;
The numerical simulation is an important tool to solve two-phase flow
problems found in several physical processes, such as oil drilling,
reservoir filling, hemodynamic and cooling of electronic components, the
latter of great importance for describing problems related to controling
flow and temperature conditions for new generation of stack processors.
It is in this scope that this project retains, for the development and
improvement of a two- phase study platform using high level numerical
simulation, described in modern language environment using
object-oriented programming, in order to study in details fluid flow
problems in microscale, specifically the characterization of flows in
microchannels with different cross section geometry. At the end of the
project, the objective is to comprehend, in detail, the dynamics of
bubbles in different types of channels to enhance the efficient
dissipation of heat in compact processing units (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt;). Indicators of
performance that will be used in the project are based on publications
produced by the professor/researcher and subject to assessments
scientific&amp;nbsp;community.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">High Performance System for Multiphase Flow Simulation in Complex Geometry</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/jcne-2016.html"/>
            <updated>2016-12-01T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2016-12-01T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/jcne-2016.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="cooling of electronics"
                        label="Cooling Of Electronics" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/faperj.png&#34; /&gt;
The numerical simulation is a essential tool to troubleshoot multiphase
flows found in many physico-chemical processes, such as the oil and gas
extraction and processing, filling of hydroelectric reservoirs,
drug-eluting transport in biological systems and cooling of high
technology electronic components, all of them of utmost importance for
achieving technology and development to the State of Rio de Janeiro.
It is in this scope that the present project is part of, aimed at improving
and adding new features on a high perfor- mance platform of multiphase
flow simulation in geometries with high level of complexity. This tool
is able to predict in details physical phenomena hard to be observed
through Experimental and analytical reproduction, such as those found in
biological systems, more specifically in the transport substances that
can cause total or partial blockage of arteries undergoing stenting for
&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CAD&lt;/span&gt; treatment and cooling of electronic by analysis of multiphase flows
in parallel channels. Indicators of performance that will be used in the
project are based on publications produced by the professor/researcher
and subject to assessments of the scientific&amp;nbsp;community.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Reduce Operating and Environmental Costs of Thermal Power Generation System (INT-FAPERJ)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/int-2016.html"/>
            <updated>2016-08-29T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2016-08-29T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/int-2016.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="thermal power"
                        label="Thermal Power" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/faperj.png&#34; /&gt;
A third of the capacity of power generation in Rio de Janeiro and Brazil
comes from power plants. According to the Ministry of Mines and Energy,
the thermal power generation using coal corresponds to twenty-two plants
with an installed capacity of about 3.&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;600MW&lt;/span&gt;. Considering the low quality
of Brazilian coal and low calorific value, large coal volume is required
to obtain adequate temperature conditions in thermoelectric generation
systems.
As a direct consequence, high pollutant emission rates to the
environment are present in the process, and increased wear on the metal
parts inside the boiler depending on the composition of the ash formed
by combustion of coal. This project aims to promote the training and
development of students and minimize environmental impacts and
mechanical caused by the high amount of fossil fuel. a detailed
investigation of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CO2&lt;/span&gt; transport and hydrodynamics present will be held in
the industrial process, and the use of specific metal coatings in
critical areas of boilers found in thermoelectric generation systems of
the State of Rio de Janeiro and&amp;nbsp;Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Multiphase Flows for Cooling of Electronics (INST-FAPERJ)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/inst-2015.html"/>
            <updated>2015-11-26T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2015-11-26T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/inst-2015.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="cooling of electronics"
                        label="Cooling Of Electronics" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/faperj.png&#34; /&gt;
Multiphase flow are characterized by the presence of an interface
separating two substances which may or may not be in the same phase. The
presence of such physical interface increases the complexity of the flow
and as a direct consequence, much of the multiphase problems encountered
with difficult engineering solution.
Undeniably, the numerical simulation is an important tool to solve
multiphase problems encountered in oil extraction processes, reservoir
filling, cooling of electronic components and food synthesis processes
in biochemical systems. It is in this scope that the present project is
part, for the development and improvement of a multiphase study platform
using numerical simulation of high-level, described in modern numerical
tools in an environment-oriented programming language objects. The
objective is to use this numerical simulator for the detailed study of
multiphase flow found in relevant engineering problems to the research
lines of the Department of Mechanical Engineering at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UERJ&lt;/span&gt;. The
performance indicators that will be used in the project are based on
publications produced by the teacher / researcher and submitted to the
scientific community&amp;nbsp;assessments.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Simulation of Biological Systems using Dynamic Meshes (APQ1-FAPERJ)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/apq1-2015.html"/>
            <updated>2015-10-29T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2015-10-29T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/apq1-2015.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="biological system"
                        label="Biological System" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/faperj.png&#34; /&gt;
The numerical simulation is an important tool to solve biphasic problems
encountered in various physical processes, such as oil drilling,
reservoir filling, cooling of electronic components and substances
transport processes in biological systems, the latter being of great
importance for the description of problems related to coronary artery
disease (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CAD&lt;/span&gt;).
It is in this scope that the present project is part, for
the development and improvement of a two-phase study platform using
numerical simulation of high-level, described in modern numerical tools
in an environment-oriented programming language objects in order to
study in detail flows found in biological problems, specifically in the
transport of substances that can cause partial or complete blockage of
arteries undergoing stenting for treatment of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CAD&lt;/span&gt;. The performance
indicators that will be used in the project are based on publications
produced by the teacher / researcher and submitted to the scientific
community&amp;nbsp;assessments.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Thermal Management of High Power Microsystems Using Multiphase Flows</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/thermapower-2015.html"/>
            <updated>2015-04-17T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2015-04-17T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/thermapower-2015.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="cooling of electronics"
                        label="Cooling Of Electronics" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/eu.png&#34; /&gt;
Increased functionality and power consumption of microdevices and high
power electronics has come at a cost: power dissipation and heating.
This heat must be dissipated to ensure reliable operation of such
devices in both earthly and reduced gravity environments (eg space
industry), without adversely affecting their performance. With a highly
competitive world market, worth tens of billions of Euros, it is
imperative for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; to gain a competitive position in this field
(currently led by &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt; and China).
The proposed work is an important step towards developing novel,
efficient and reliable thermal management via phase-change through
sustained international collaboration between top research groups in &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt;,
&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt;, Canada, Brazil, Japan and China. These include 17 experienced
researchers from University of Edinburgh, Shanghai Jiaotong University,
Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne, University System of Maryland
Foundation, University of Nottingham, York University Toronto, Kyushu
University, Kobe University and Universidade do Estado do Rio de
Janeiro. These partners have complementary expertise in
microfabrication, surface characterisation, experimental techniques,
analytical and numerical modelling. The collaboration enables knowledge
transfer and access to unique facilities such as those at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;, Intel,
Hua Wei, Siltech, Bombardier, Brazilian Furnas, Petrobras,
Eletronuclear, State Government of Rio de Janeiro, Brazilian agencies
for development (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FINEP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FAPERJ&lt;/span&gt;), Hitachi, Toshiba, Mitsubishi, Kansai
Electric Power Co. and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;, reinforcing the research standing of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; in
this crucial technological area. It also offers a unique opportunity for
training 20 early stage researchers in state-of-art experimental and
modelling techniques for phase-change and microfabrication. In addition
to regular consortium meetings, technical workshops and research
publications, we propose two summer schools at Shanghai (supported by
&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;RCUK&lt;/span&gt;) and Lausanne and several exchange programmes to sustain long-term
interaction between the&amp;nbsp;partners.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">French Chair at the State University of Rio de Janeiro</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/catedras-2015.html"/>
            <updated>2014-11-17T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2014-11-17T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/catedras-2015.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element method"
                        label="Finite Element Method" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/professor/catedras.png&#34; /&gt;
The modelling of rising bubbles in tubes or pipes is an important
challenge, specifically in complex geometries, such pipes of non-uniform
diameter. Such phenomena can be observed in oil wells or food
processing. The objective of this study is to quantify experimentally
and simulate numerically the rising of fluid in another immiscible fluid
in a vertical conical pipe.
It is well know that there are several rising regimes depending on the
bubble size, the tube diameter, the fluid densities, viscosities and the
surface tension. There are few quantitative studies using conical pipes.
The goal of this project is to compare some experiments conducted in
France and the finite-element arbitrary Lagrangien-Eulerian method that
was developed in Rio de Janeiro. The study proposed here is fundamental
and aims at improving our understanding of dynamical behaviour of
two-phase flow. The outcomes of this knowledge can have an impact on the
petroleum and chemical sectors, but can also benefit to renewable energy
and environmental&amp;nbsp;engineering.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Post-Doc (UERJ)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/postdoc2.html"/>
            <updated>2013-11-02T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2013-11-02T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/postdoc2.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element"
                        label="Finite Element" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="surface tension"
                        label="Surface Tension" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;sin&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/postdoc/gesar4.png&#34; /&gt;
The topic of the post-doc is numerical two-phase flows with emphasis in
micro-macro two-phase flows in capillaries with different geometries
found in many applications within the oil and gas field. The work is
being performed in Gesar Group - &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UERJ&lt;/span&gt;. (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GESAR&lt;/span&gt;) at the State University
of Rio de Janeiro (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UERJ&lt;/span&gt;). More info will be updated&amp;nbsp;soon!&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Post-Doc (MIT)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/postdoc1.html"/>
            <updated>2012-08-01T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2012-08-01T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/postdoc1.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite volume"
                        label="Finite Volume" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="turbulence"
                        label="Turbulence" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="nuclear"
                        label="Nuclear" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;constr&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/postdoc/mit-logo.png&#34; /&gt;
The topic of the post-doc is boiling and condensation in convective flow
with multiple bubbles found in nuclear reactors. The work was performed
in the Nuclear Science and Engineering (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NSE&lt;/span&gt;) at the Massachussetts
Institute of Technology (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Motivation and&amp;nbsp;approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accurate prediction of the bubble size, which depends on the bubble
  departure diameter (initial condition) and the condensation&amp;nbsp;rate;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWR&lt;/span&gt; flow conditions including bubble sizes,
  shapes, non-dimensional numbers,&amp;nbsp;etc;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literature review of data and empirical correlations for bubble&amp;nbsp;condensation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benchmark test cases to spot one physical effect at a time are divided
  as: Heat Transfer from a solid sphere, 1-dimensional Stefan Problem,
  Isothermal Bubble rise, Bubble growth in a liquid at rest (boiling),
  Bubble collapse in a liquid at rest&amp;nbsp;(condensation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/media/images/research/postdoc/nuclear.png 
align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/media/images/research/postdoc/bubbles.png 
align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Table shows benchmark results for 2 different mesh refinement levels
compared to experimental results for a isothermal rising bubble. In
Figure with red background, the numerical simulation of a bubble growth
in a liquid at rest is compared to the well known Scriven solution for
the bubble history. The Table presents a summary of conditions and
applicability for pressurized water reactor (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWR&lt;/span&gt;) and 4 different models
found in the literature. It shows that none of the currently available
correlations is suitable for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWR&lt;/span&gt; application. These 4 correlations are
plotted in Figures for the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWR&lt;/span&gt; conditions. As can be seen, the
discrepancy of predicting bubble history and Nuc is large among&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/media/images/research/postdoc/results1.png 
align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/media/images/research/postdoc/table-results.png 
align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/media/images/research/postdoc/table.png 
align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusions and further&amp;nbsp;work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correlations were testes using different conditions and further
  evaluated at the pressurized water reactor conditions in terms of the
  bubble history (beta) and the condensation Nusselt number Nuc during the
  condensation process of a detached vapor&amp;nbsp;bubble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current standard tool for prediction of liquid-to-bubble heat transfer
  is the Ranz and Marshall’s correlation (Ranz and Marshall, Jr., 1952).
  It was found that the available resources are insufficient to describe
  accurately the condensation process occurring at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWR&lt;/span&gt; conditions.
  However, we suggest the Chen and Meyinger’s correlation due to the
  easiness of implementation in numerical codes and its linear evolution
  with time&amp;nbsp;(Fo);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have started direct numerical simulations of the bubble
  condensation process in subcooled flow boiling using the commercial
  code&amp;nbsp;TransAT. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Ph.D.</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/phd.html"/>
            <updated>2012-07-30T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2012-07-30T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/phd.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="bubble"
                        label="Bubble" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="surface tension"
                        label="Surface Tension" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="curvature"
                        label="Curvature" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="drop"
                        label="Drop" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;vortex&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/phd/singleVortex.png&#34; /&gt;
The topic of the doctorate is two-phase flow and heat transfer in
microchannels. One of the major aspects of this thesis will be to extend
the single phase code (developed during the masters studies) and
implement two-phase and heat transfer bringing the surface tension
effects into the code for elongated bubble flows, annular flows and
bubbly flows (for both evaporating flows and perhaps also for some
condensing flows).
&lt;img alt=&#34;disk&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/phd/3Dbubble.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Finite Element Method (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FEM&lt;/span&gt;) and the Arbitrary
Lagrangian-Eulerian (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ALE&lt;/span&gt;) framework will be used to achieve such a task.
Another interesting aspect could be for an isolated bubble growing at a
wall in a cross-flow in a microchannel with down stream coalescence of
the train of departing bubbles. All these works are done in the Heat and
Mass Transfer Laboratory (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LTCM&lt;/span&gt;) at the Swiss Federal Institute of
Technology in Lausanne (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EPFL&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">GESAR (post-M.Sc.)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/postmsc.html"/>
            <updated>2007-04-01T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2007-04-01T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/postmsc.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="laminar"
                        label="Laminar" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="reservoir"
                        label="Reservoir" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="single phase"
                        label="Single Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;res1&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/postmsc/simU225.png&#34; /&gt;
From 2007 to mid-2008 I worked as a young researcher in the Group for
Study and Simulations of Reservoir Filling (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GESAR&lt;/span&gt;) . This one-year
experience brought me the necessary skills for large code development,
since the multi-disciplinary project required experience in many
different areas such as engineering, biology, chemistry and mathematics.
The project consisted in numerical simulation of hydropower reservoirs
filling.
&lt;img alt=&#34;res1&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/postmsc/simC225.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Navier-Stokes&amp;#8217;s equation was used to describe the behaviour
of the interaction between the surrounded nature (nutrients, vegetation,
chemical components) and the flow itself. The previous master&amp;#8217;s code was
improved and massively tested against important nature phenomenas which
occurs due to the filling of large Brazilian reservoirs. The Finite
Element Method had been used for the mathematical discretization using
triangular (2D) and tetrahedral (3D) elements. The final result is the
development of a powerful software able to predict the natural variables
found in a generic hydropower reservoirs&amp;nbsp;filling.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">M.Sc.</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/msc.html"/>
            <updated>2005-03-20T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2005-03-20T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/msc.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="numerical"
                        label="Numerical" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="single phase"
                        label="Single Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="transition"
                        label="Transition" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="finite element"
                        label="Finite Element" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;disk&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/msc/disk.png&#34; /&gt;
Followed by the end of my bachelor&amp;#8217;s project, I started my masters
studies at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UFRJ&lt;/span&gt;) in the
Metallurgical and Materials Engineering Department (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;COPPE&lt;/span&gt;). The period
of two years is required to receive the Master&amp;#8217;s degree and during this
period we must follow some courses and write a dissertation based on a
specific theme.
We have chosen to follow three directions of courses:
scientific computing, mathematics and fluid mechanics, all of them were
done in their respective departments. The aim of the masters thesis was
to develop a three dimensional Finite Element code, under the
object-oriented paradigm, to simulate the flow field close to an
electrochemical cell immerse in h3SO4 solution. The Navier-Stokes&amp;#8217;s
equations were used to model the real system. We used the
Semi-Lagrangian approach to treat the convective (non-linear) term,
present in the equations, which is one of the most problematic issue in
such a modelling. The others terms namely pressure and viscous terms,
were discretized by the standard Galerkin method. The final linear
system Ax=b was treated by the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LU&lt;/span&gt; projection method, thus decoupling
velocity and pressure in two smaller systems. In 2007 I received my
master&amp;#8217;s degree&amp;nbsp;(M.Sc.).&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">B.Eng.</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/research/bsc.html"/>
            <updated>2000-01-03T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2000-01-03T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/research/bsc.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="single phase"
                        label="Single Phase" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="experimental"
                        label="Experimental" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="wind tunnel"
                        label="Wind Tunnel" />
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="turbulence"
                        label="Turbulence" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;avelino&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/research/bsc/avelino.png&#34; /&gt;
I received my bachelor diploma (B.Eng.) in mechanical engineering at the
State University of Rio de Janeiro (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UERJ&lt;/span&gt;) in 2005. In early 2003, I
started to be involved in research by participating in monitoring and
undergraduate research. During this period I focoused my studies on
fluid dynamics and finally presented my bachelor project
entitled &amp;#8220;Atmospheric Boundary Layer Simulation in Wild Tunnel&amp;#8221; where we
had analyzed experimentally the effects of fluid flow and its boundary
layer over a tropical and dense forest. This project had been started
after some issues of local measurement and thus the experimental
simulation in wind tunnel was performed to understand the atmospheric
conditions in the Amazon Rainforest. After this project I received the
mechanical engineer&amp;nbsp;diploma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/images/research/bsc/avelino.png&#34;&gt;My Man Jeeves by &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PG&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Wodehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>