<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        BASIC blog full text feed    </title>
        <link href="/videos/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2023-08-13T07:21:43Z</updated>

    <id>/videos/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">Channel width comparison for 2D Two-Phase flows</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/1.html"/>
            <updated>2022-09-19T06:58:08Z</updated>
            <published>2022-09-19T06:58:08Z</published>
            <id>/videos/1.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nH6Y9hlqE5I?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test shows the deceleration of a rising bubble due to the distance between lateral walls. As can be seen, the larger is the channel width the faster is the rising bubble. The right hand side figure does not even arrive at the middle of the channel length for the exactly same parameters and time step to all simulat
ions presented in this video. The background colors represent the variation of pressure along the channel, where red color indicates high pressure and blue color low&amp;nbsp;pressure.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising bubble in quiescent liquid using arbitrary quadrilateral mesh</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/2.html"/>
            <updated>2022-09-10T15:32:30Z</updated>
            <published>2022-09-10T15:32:30Z</published>
            <id>/videos/2.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VWdGCPesO7w?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulation using the Finite Element method for 2D Two-Phase flows with deformable interface in arbitrary quadrilateral&amp;nbsp;mesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-dimensional parameters of the&amp;nbsp;simulation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re = 10  # Reynolds
We = 10   # Weber
Fr = 1.0  # Froude
dynamic viscosity ratio = 2
density ratio =&amp;nbsp;100&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Efficient Laplacian Smoothing on Quadrilateral Mesh</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/3.html"/>
            <updated>2022-09-05T03:13:39Z</updated>
            <published>2022-09-05T03:13:39Z</published>
            <id>/videos/3.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4LICDKw7eO0?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This animations show the effect of the Laplacian Smoothing operation on quadrilateral mesh in a rectangular domain. Such a mesh is commonly used in Finite Element Analysis and can be further employed in single- and two-phase flow simulations. The main advantage of arbitrary quadrilateral meshes over triangular meshes i
s the accuracy of the discrete&amp;nbsp;operators.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Efficient Laplacian Smoothing on Quadrilateral Mesh</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/4.html"/>
            <updated>2022-09-05T03:13:39Z</updated>
            <published>2022-09-05T03:13:39Z</published>
            <id>/videos/4.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TepROp44QpY?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This animations show the effect of the Laplacian Smoothing operation on quadrilateral mesh in a rectangular domain. Such a mesh is commonly used in Finite Element Analysis and can be further employed in single- and two-phase flow simulations. The main advantage of arbitrary quadrilateral meshes over triangular meshes i
s the accuracy of the discrete&amp;nbsp;operators.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Passive particle transport of 200 particles</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/5.html"/>
            <updated>2022-03-24T00:05:18Z</updated>
            <published>2022-03-24T00:05:18Z</published>
            <id>/videos/5.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/co1ZbsTu6yU?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows a 2D passive particle transport of 200 particles in a channel with an obstacle. The motion is only given by the update position differential equation X^n+1 = X^n + v * dt, where n+1 is the future postion, n is the current position and v is the flow velocity, which does not depend on the particle&amp;#8217;s moti
on. As can be seen, particles in the middle of the channel have slow speed, while the others are faster. The numerical simulation was developed using the Finite Element method in an unstructured triangular mesh generated using the Gmsh&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Bloodstream flow with drug-eluting stents in coronary artery</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/6.html"/>
            <updated>2020-11-12T19:40:52Z</updated>
            <published>2020-11-12T19:40:52Z</published>
            <id>/videos/6.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RSvkEmEWJlE?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video shows the numerical simulation of bloodstream flow in coronary artery with drug-eluting stents implanted to reduce buildup of fat deposition. The simulation was made using the Finite Element method and an unstructured triangular mesh and high order interpolation. The results reveal an interesting drug diffusi
on dynamics after the fat deposition that may change blood viscosity in a long-term&amp;nbsp;period.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Slug flow in sinusoidal channel</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/7.html"/>
            <updated>2020-11-12T19:31:01Z</updated>
            <published>2020-11-12T19:31:01Z</published>
            <id>/videos/7.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hiYFtzWzLEE?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a numerical simulation of slug flow in sinusoidal channel using the finite element method and the moving-mesh/moving-boundary technique found in (https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cma.2020.112820). As can be seen 3 confined drops are flowing thru the corrugated channel and its cross-sectional variation changes the drop
s shapes periodically. The center drop is pushed forward and coalescence with the front drop may&amp;nbsp;occurs.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Jet stream during conversation (COVID-19/SARS-CoV-2)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/8.html"/>
            <updated>2020-10-21T01:16:29Z</updated>
            <published>2020-10-21T01:16:29Z</published>
            <id>/videos/8.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fuHmX3Qx-fQ?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This animation shows the solution of a 2-dimensional flow jet stream during conversation of a human being possible contaminated with &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;COVID&lt;/span&gt;-19. This study aims at investigate the persistence of a certain number of droplets with viral load in&amp;nbsp;air.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">2d Particle Collisions</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/9.html"/>
            <updated>2020-06-21T17:38:42Z</updated>
            <published>2020-06-21T17:38:42Z</published>
            <id>/videos/9.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MHq0zI-QjXI?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows the collisions of several particles with different sizes in a closed rectangular domain. Momentum is conserved in an isolated system with full elastic shocks between particles with different mass. As can be seen in this model, the heavier particles do not change their velocities too much with collision
s. Also, if particles hit any wall, the particles are redirected considering a suitable smooth surface and according to its normal vector. This simulation was carried out using the Python language and took approximately 25s to be accomplished in a standard personal&amp;nbsp;computer.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising of air bubble in water-sugar solution (Bhaga and Weber, 1981)</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/10.html"/>
            <updated>2020-03-03T06:29:20Z</updated>
            <published>2020-03-03T06:29:20Z</published>
            <id>/videos/10.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FaEt8mLmgSg?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This movie shows the numerical solution of an initially spherical air bubble in a quiescent water-sugar solution using a moving frame view point where the bubble&amp;#8217;s centroid remains fixed in space while fluid flows downward. In this approach, the interface mesh is built as a set of interconnected nodes and finite triang
le elements. The red and blue colours of the  background tetrahedral mesh represent the horizontal velocity component.  Red color is positive velocity and blue color is negative velocity. As can be seen, in the current approach, very low adaptive remeshing is required since bubble is fixed in space. Additionally, only the normal component of the velocity is used to move nodes lying at the the interface, thus avoiding extensive remeshing at the surface. This approach leeds to very accurate results when simulating two-phase flow systems with high interface&amp;nbsp;deformation.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">VIV ALE-FE</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/11.html"/>
            <updated>2019-07-08T09:55:24Z</updated>
            <published>2019-07-08T09:55:24Z</published>
            <id>/videos/11.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EvcrE9t0GUI?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;VIVALE&lt;/span&gt; - Vortex-induced vibration using Arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian Finite Element Method for 2D simulation. In this video, the cylinder motion is controlled by a simple analytical function and adaptive mesh refinement is used to control mesh quality near the&amp;nbsp;cylinder.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rotating disk flow</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/12.html"/>
            <updated>2016-09-02T21:16:46Z</updated>
            <published>2016-09-02T21:16:46Z</published>
            <id>/videos/12.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NPmCHwuz3W0?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot shows the evolution of the 3 boundary layers with time, according to the transient solution of the Navier-Stokes equations for the Rotating Disk Flow problem (see Schlichting Boundary Layer&amp;nbsp;Theory)&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Sessile drop</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/13.html"/>
            <updated>2013-03-21T23:23:04Z</updated>
            <published>2013-03-21T23:23:04Z</published>
            <id>/videos/13.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nZp1Y0_DM88?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this test case, the numerical solution of a sessile drop is compared to the exact solution given by a set of ordinary equations for a 3D axisymmetric drop, both compared during the last 2 seconds of this animation. The test consists in releasing a drop and, due to gravitational force, the drop approaches the wall. I
mmediately before adhering the wall, the drop assumes a steady shape, which can be compared to the exact solution. The interface between the fluids is represented by a triangular surface mesh and the 3D domain by a tetrahedron mesh. The animation is colored by the pressure&amp;nbsp;field.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">3D vortex field</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/14.html"/>
            <updated>2013-02-10T19:51:41Z</updated>
            <published>2013-02-10T19:51:41Z</published>
            <id>/videos/14.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BVYVxs0GS90?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3-dimensional vortex field test case. This particular benchmark tests extensively the remeshing methodology implemented in our &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CFD&lt;/span&gt; code. The test consists in applying a 3d vortex field on a sphere which will be complete distorted in t=0.5T, where T is the total time of the simulation. From t=0.5T to t=T, the vortex fie
ld is reverted and the original sphere shape is thus expected. The characteristic mesh length is L=1/50. The literature shows equivalent result using a different approach for mesh length L=1/256, which proves that the proposed remshing method is&amp;nbsp;accurate.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Single vortex simulation</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/15.html"/>
            <updated>2012-11-03T14:14:25Z</updated>
            <published>2012-11-03T14:14:25Z</published>
            <id>/videos/15.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AOBfeWk_vxM?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this test case, the remeshing methodology is massively tested while the bubble is subjected to a single vortex field. The tetrahedral background mesh is colored by the magnitude of the vortex field velocity. The red color represents high velocity, while the blue one stands for low intensity. As can be seen, the volu
me and interface remeshing algorihtms keep the finite elements with excellent aspect ratio (height, width, area and volume), thus avoiding low quality elements such as silver and kite types. Additionally, the phase volumes are kept constant, showing that the used methodology is suitable for large&amp;nbsp;deformations.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Zalesak&#39;s rotating sphere test case</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/16.html"/>
            <updated>2012-11-01T06:40:39Z</updated>
            <published>2012-11-01T06:40:39Z</published>
            <id>/videos/16.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRsrwpmGC10?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zalesak&amp;#8217;s test case is a common benchmark to evaluate the reconstruction of the interface while the Zalesak sphere is rotating. The background flow is imposed with no need of solving the Navier-Stokes equations. As can be seen in the animation and despite the coarse mesh used on this test case, our moving mesh meth
odology keeps the interface sharp and with minimal numerical diffusion after many rotations. The red color represents the sharp interface (triangular surface) and the blue stands for the outer mesh (tetrahedrons). The green color is due to the interpolation of the rendering program&amp;nbsp;Paraview.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Squeezing of 2 bubbles</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/17.html"/>
            <updated>2012-07-16T14:08:05Z</updated>
            <published>2012-07-16T14:08:05Z</published>
            <id>/videos/17.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nBBm-l3vLi4?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modeling of last stage of two bubble&amp;#8217;s coalescence process. The animation shows three different views of the same simulation to illustrate the approaching of two bubbles. Using the 3D &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ALE&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FEM&lt;/span&gt; code, we are able to study the physical phenomena that takes place before the unexplored and non-trivial process of bubble coale&amp;nbsp;scence.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">cross section triangle</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/18.html"/>
            <updated>2012-07-16T14:08:05Z</updated>
            <published>2012-07-16T14:08:05Z</published>
            <id>/videos/18.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2nVAMiyqsxI?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-phase flow of a single bubble in a triangular channel. The Navier-Stokes equations are discretized through the Arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian framework in which the interface between fluids are accessed sharply by defining a triangular surface embed on the tetrahedral mesh. In such a particular simulation, the confi
ned bubble is deformed due to the wall efects and its shape corresponds to the cross section shape of the channel. Three views are available to look in details the flow: single bubble side view, rear view and a cut plane along the channel which describes the remeshing methodology of the outer tetrahedron&amp;nbsp;mesh.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising air bubble in sugar syrup solution</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/19.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/19.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2nEl0GazNsk?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gravity-driven flow of an air bubble in sugar-syrup solution. The result was compared to the White and Beardmore flow pattern map (1962) and good agreement was found for the rising velocity of the air bubble and the liquid film&amp;nbsp;thickness.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising air bubble in sucrose solution</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/20.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/20.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tn9I9t86vTo?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gravity-driven flow of an air bubble in sucrose solution. The result was compared to the White and Beardmore flow pattern map (1962) and good agreement was found for the  rising velocity of the air bubble and liquid film&amp;nbsp;thickness.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising air bubble in sucrose solution</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/21.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/21.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WrmnBh7mTNs?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gravity-driven flow of an air bubble in sucrose solution. The result was compared to the White and Beardmore flow pattern map (1962) and good agreement was found for the rising velocity of the air bubble and liquid film&amp;nbsp;thickness.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Two-phase flow evaporation in microchannel</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/22.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/22.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rhhXlrcRHI4?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat and Mass transfer of refrigerant R1234ze in square cross-section microchannels with a constant heat flux applied on the bottom of the domain. Red color represent high temperature and blue stands for low&amp;nbsp;temperature.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Microchannel two-phase flow of refrigerant R1234ze.</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/23.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/23.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/APDQFLFARZ4?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-phase slug flow in square cross-section microchannels. 3D Finite Element simulation was successfully carried out to predict bubble shape, velocity, liquid slug and liquid film thickness in the scope of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CMOSAIC&lt;/span&gt; project financed by NanoTera in Switzerland. The liquid and gas phases correspond to the refrigerant R
1234ze and the channel width is&amp;nbsp;100^-6m.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Rising air bubble in glycerol solution</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/24.html"/>
            <updated>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</updated>
            <published>2012-06-05T15:52:11Z</published>
            <id>/videos/24.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IIDEIx-F3iQ?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gravity-driven flow of an air bubble in sugar-syrup solution. The 3D equations were discretized using the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ALE&lt;/span&gt; framework and the Finite Element Method. The numerical result was compared to the White and Beardmore flow pattern map (1962) and good agreement was found for the rising velocity. Bubble shape and liquid film t
hickness were successfully compared to the&amp;nbsp;literature.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">2D Rising Bubble Heat Transfer</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/25.html"/>
            <updated>2012-02-03T22:37:34Z</updated>
            <published>2012-02-03T22:37:34Z</published>
            <id>/videos/25.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HNsdHehXN5A?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2D simulation of a rising bubble with heat transfer. The bubble, lighter then the surrounding fluid, rises and moves towards the heat interface (green color) . The non-dimensional numbers used in this simulations were Re = 200, Sc = 1000, We = 10, mu_in = 0.5, mu_out = 1.0, rho_out = 1.0, rho_in = 0.01. On the right ha
nd side, the inner and interface meshes are shown. It can be seen that after a certain period of time the bubble does not rise straight, instead the bubble oscillates from one side to another and changes its&amp;nbsp;shape.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">2D Heat Transfer Bubble Rising</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/26.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-28T11:25:57Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-28T11:25:57Z</published>
            <id>/videos/26.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NScl-onahbI?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rising of a single bubble immersed in a fluid where the bottom part (red) is heated and has temperature higher then the upper part (blue). The bubble is then release and due to buoyancy effect, it crosses the heat transition line (green color). The heat transfer process takes place into the bubble dynamic and due to th
e bubble rising speed, the heat is advected along with the bubble, thus the two different temperature zones are consequently mixed. The 2D mesh can be seen on the left hand side figure and it comprises many triangles interconnected that need to be rearranged due to the high velocity&amp;nbsp;gradient.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">3D Point Deletion Strategy</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/27.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</published>
            <id>/videos/27.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W-BRGcCDmsk?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interface between fluids is represented by a set of points, edges and facets. These facets are triangles which are part of the tetrahedron mesh. Each triangle represents the shared facet of two adjacent tetrahedrons. As can be seen, while the surface movies with respect to the flow, the elements are compressed spoi
ling the their quality ratios, thus the algorithm should remove excessive concentration of points and remesh locally the hole formed by the deletion&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">3D Point Insertion Strategy</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/28.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</published>
            <id>/videos/28.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O_XaZa5wyOU?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interface between fluids is represented by a set of points, edges and facets. These facets are triangles which are part of the tetrahedron mesh. Each triangle represents the shared facet of two adjacent tetrahedrons. As can be seen, while the surface movies with respect to the flow, the elements are stretched spoil
ing their quality ratios, thus the algorithm should insert points when an edge becomes bigger then a calculated value. Such a value is based on the local curvature and its required&amp;nbsp;precision.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">3D Air-Water Flow</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/29.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</published>
            <id>/videos/29.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-6wKVQsIUqw?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rising of a single air bubble in a stagnant column of water has been simulated. The 3-dimensional two-phase flow phenomena can be numerically predicted. At the leftmost frame, the interface between fluid is represented by a set of points, edges and triangular facets which are part of the tetrahedron domain mesh. Th
e middle frame is a contour plot of the same interface and the rightmost one is a side view of the 3-dimensional domain. Due to its properties, the flow field changes the initially spherical shape while the bubble rises, thus affecting all the surrounded&amp;nbsp;fluid.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">2D Microchannel Coalescence</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/30.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</published>
            <id>/videos/30.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qzoG_wGDXTU?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulation of 2D microchannel two-phase flow. The equations are written in the Arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian framework (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ALE&lt;/span&gt;) through the Finite Element method (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FEM&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ANJOS&lt;/span&gt; et al. (2013). The bubble velocity profile is shown on the top of the figure where the highest horizontal speed is represented by the red 
color and the lowest one is represented by the blue color. The mesh used in this simulation is shown in the bottom part of the figure, where the red and blue triangles represent the vapor and liquid phase respectively. Three bubbles are initially distributed along the channel, the last two bubbles coalesce, generating one elongated bubble. This shows a transition regime from slug to elongated bubble&amp;nbsp;flow.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">3D Air-Water-Sugar Flow</title>
            <author><name>Gustavo R Anjos</name></author>
            <link href="/videos/31.html"/>
            <updated>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</updated>
            <published>2011-11-14T15:39:58Z</published>
            <id>/videos/31.html</id>
                        <category   scheme="/res.url/tags"
                        term="two-phase"
                        label="Two-Phase" />
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CBv8NA5pEQk?rel=0&#34;frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulation of 3-dimensional two-phase flow is performed to predict the rising of an air bubble in a initially stagnant water-sugar solution. At the leftmost frame, the interface between fluid is represented by a set of points, edges and triangular facets which are part of the tetrahedron domain mesh. The midd
le frame is a contour plot of the same interface and the rightmost one is a side view of the 3-dimensional domain. Due to the flow nature, the initially spherical shape deforms while in ascension, then later the air bubble converges to its final shape as show in this&amp;nbsp;animation.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>